我是Animagraffs的作者Jacob O'Neal
I'm Jacob O'Neal creator of Animagraffs.
本期带大家了解F1赛车
And this is how a Formula 1 race car works.
先从气动组件说起
Let's start with aerodynamics,
气动组件
它们是赛车直接与外界空气相互作用的部分
which is how the car interacts with and moves through the air around it.
我们大致了解一下结论就好
it's best to focus on overall theory here
别死抠某个气动细节然后掉进流体力学的地狱
to avoid getting lost in the absolute maze of individual aerodynamic features.
前翼整体是向上翘起的曲线 可以让空气像视频中那样流动
The front wing curves upward forcing air to move around it in such a way
在上面产生高压区 下面产生低压区
that a high pressure area forms above the wing with lower pressure beneath.
这种压力差可以把车按在赛道上 也就是"下压力"
This pressure difference contributes to a kind of suction force called downforce
that pushes or sticks the car to the track
前翼两侧末端 不同压力差的气流相会
Where the wing ends and these different pressure zones meet,
两边一打架就变成了螺旋的涡流
the air crashes into itself, creating a spiraling vortex.
涡流会产生阻力 让赛车减速
Vortices cause drag which tugs at the car, slowing it down.
而前翼两侧的竖挡板能缓解涡流的形成 减小阻力
A cap on the wingtip interrupts vortex formation for a less intense effect.
与之相反的是前翼内侧的弧形小翼
In contrast, the pointed curved in surfaces on the inside edge of the wing
它会刻意产生涡流 并引导至赛车底板周围
intentionally shape and direct a vortex around the floor of the car,
对通过底板的干净气流起到密封作用
sealing in the clean air that passes beneath.
所以虽然涡流会产生阻力
So while vortices do cause drag,
但它同时也是分离 密封不同区域气流的有力工具
they're also a useful tool to separate and seal in different areas of airflow.
长期以来F1赛车都没有挡泥板
As a matter of tradition, F1 cars don't have fenders.
开放式的车轮会产生大量的脏空气乱流
And the open spinning wheel and tire combination is a major source of dirty turbulent air.
这样的乱流很难预测
Turbulent air is unpredictable,
对气动组件产生下压力不会有太大作用
and not very useful for aerodynamic goals, like generating downforce.
所以在轮胎后方 会有破风板来整理这些气流
Directly behind the tires, the bargeboards condition or clean up some of this airflow
同时还能让大量脏空气远离车身
while also pushing lots of dirty air away from the body.
赛车底板与赛道之间的狭小空隙
The narrow gap between the car floor and the track
为整个赛车产生了相当可观的下压力
turns the entire floor into a giant downforce generator,
气流被压缩 以相比于车顶不同的速度与压强加速流经赛车底部
as air squeezes, thins and rushes beneath the car
at a different rate and pressure than overhead air.
底板整体是向前倾斜的 称为倾角(rake) 会在最窄的地方产生很强的低压
The floor has a forward tilt or rake that creates very low pressure at its narrowest point
又能让空气在流出后部时顺利与环境空气压力融合
but allows air to more smoothly rejoin ambient air pressure as it flows out the back.
赛车尾部的扩散器用明显向上的曲率形状放大了这一效应
A diffuser at the rear amplifies this goal with its more pronounced upward curvature.
扩散器有垂直的沟道 可以引导空气从车底涌出时形成的巨大涡流
The diffuser has vertical veins to control and direct the massive vortices that form behind the car
as air pours out from underneath.
清洁空气被引导到侧面的吊舱用于冷却
Clean air is directed into the side pods for cooling purposes.
这股气流流经赛车内部后会从尾翼下方流出
This stream passes through the car and out the back beneath the rear wing.
轮廓平滑的车身引导气流在各种极端环境下都能优雅拂过车身
The smoothly contoured body guides air streams gracefully around bodywork
for predictable handling under extreme conditions.
向上翘起的尾翼是另一个产生下压力的关键组件
The upward curved rear wing which is another critical downforce generator
它两侧的竖板有栅格缺口 可以让一些气流提前逸出
has notched end caps with gaps and louvers to allow some air to combine early,
从而调整尾翼后的涡流特性
altering and shaping rear wing vortex characteristics.
这也是在潮湿环境下
It's also where in wet conditions
大家有时能在这看到明显的雾状翼尖涡流
the noticeable misty wingtip vortices sometimes appear in plain sight
≤85mm
当减阻系统(DRS)启动时 液压作动器会抬起一部分尾翼
Hydraulic actuator tilts a section of the rear wing when the drag reduction system or DRS is engaged,
降低后部产生的下压力 提高赛车整体速度
generating less rear downforce but allowing higher overall speed.
车后大量的脏空气会让其他车辆难以接近和超车
The massive area of dirty air behind the car
can make it difficult for other cars to approach and overtake.
值得注意的是在未来几年 F1赛车的气动设计将发生重大变化
It's worth noting here that in coming years the aerodynamic design regulations for F1 cars
鼓励更紧密的跟车与超车
are set for major changes to encourage closer racing and overtaking.
到那时 尾部的气流可能看起来更像这样 而不是现在这样大片的脏气流
The airflow pattern might look more like this than the current wide dirty wake.
然后我们来瞧瞧F1赛车的瓤 先说核心的支撑结构
Now let's go underneath this exterior bodywork, starting with the core support structure.
核心支撑结构
有碳纤维制造的单壳体车身(monocoque)
A carbon fiber shell called a monocoque,
发动机头和缸体
the engine heads and block,
外加变速箱外壳 构成了所有其他系统的主要支撑结构
and the gearbox enclosure form the main structural support for all other systems.
下面就没有额外框架或底盘了
There's no additional frame or chassis underneath.
悬架
前后悬架的部件很接近
Both front and back suspension setups share similar components.
上下层的叉臂外加推杆或拉杆
Upper and lower wishbone arms with a push or pull rod.
叉臂是刚性的结构支撑 垂直行程有限
The wishbones are rigid structural supports with limited vertical travel.
在不存在热量问题的赛车前部 叉臂直接连接到单壳体车身上
At the front where heat isn't an issue, wishbones are directly attached to the monocoque
并有简单的弹性接头 可以在负载下弯曲
and have simple flexure joints designed to bend under load.
赛车后部 发动机的热量可能很高 因此使用的是球形轴承
At the rear where engine heat can be intense spherical bearings are used.
推拉杆是活动的地方
The push or pull rod is where the action happens
视频中的模型 前面是推杆 后面是拉杆
Our model has push rods in the front and pull rods in the back
只用于展现这套系统是什么样的 是怎么推动或者拉动悬架部件的
which simplified just indicates how the system is mounted to push or pull connected suspension parts.
零件安装得越低越好 重心越低越好
If parts can be mounted down low for a lower center of gravity, all the better.
拉杆连接双臂曲柄和阻尼 在家用车上叫避震器
The pull rod connects to a rocker and damper, which we call shock absorbers in normal cars.
但是F1悬架系统不用大型盘簧
But instead of large coiled springs,
而是使用会在负载下扭转的小金属杆 称为扭杆
F1 suspension uses a small metal rod called a torsion bar that twists under load.
扭杆的一侧随着外圆柱轴移动
One side of the torsion bar moves with the outer cylindrical shaft,
而另一侧是不动的
while the other side is stationary.
两个独立悬架的两侧都与一个中央防倾杆相连 以限制车身倾斜
Both independent suspension sides are linked to a central roll bar that twists to limit body roll.
摇摆弹簧负责赛车的垂直位置 这对赛车有合适的气动特性至关重要
Heave is the vertical position of the car, which is critically important for proper aerodynamics.
在两边车轮同时向上或向下运动时 摇摆弹簧和避震器就会共同作用
The heave spring and damper cleverly come into play when both sides move up or down together,
比如直线加速或刹车时
for example during acceleration or braking,
但在其他动作中摇摆弹簧动作并不大
but are mostly inactive for other movements.
视频中模型的摇摆弹簧是一叠锥形垫圈
The heave spring in our model is a stack of flexible cone-shaped washers
在负载下会压到一起去
that compress together under load.
而垫圈的数量可以增减 从而实现微调
Washers can be added or subtracted for fine adjustments.
前悬架处理的任务与后悬架类似 但技术不同
The front suspension handles similar tasks to the rear but with different techniques.
转向系统
转向系统与前悬架密不可分
The steering system is closely packaged with front suspension.
一根横拉杆将两个轮胎连接到一个很标准的液压齿条与齿轮装置上
A track rod links each tire to a fairly standard hydraulic rack and pinion setup,
中间的转向柱延伸到驾驶舱内
with the steering column extending into the cockpit.
后悬架也有一根横拉杆 用于轮胎垂直角度的调整
The rear suspension has a track rod as well for vertical tire angle adjustment.
所有轮胎都必须用车轮系绳与车身相连
All wheels must be attached to the car with wheel tethers.
这些线缆非常坚固 防止在发生事故时车轱辘飞出去
These are strong cables that keep wheels connected to the car in the event of an accident.
规则要求线缆至少要穿过一个以上的悬挂组件 以提高安全性
They're required to pass through more than one suspension element for increased safety.
除少数例外 多数暴露在外的悬挂组件
With few exceptions, most exposed suspension elements
都是由碳纤维制成或与碳纤维结合而成 以获得更好的气动效果
are either made from or bonded with carbon fiber for better aerodynamic forms.
这也是悬挂部件被封装在车身内部的另一个主要原因
This is another major reason suspension parts are packaged inside bodywork,
要让它尽可能远离车外的呼呼大风
away from outside air wherever possible.
刹车系统
主缸和储液器储存并控制用于制动的液压油
A master cylinder and reservoir controls and stores hydraulic fluid for braking.
F1赛车有两个主缸和配套的储液器 分别用于前后制动
F1 cars have two master cylinders and accompanying reservoirs for front and rear brakes respectively.
油缸的一端连接制动踏板 另一端是制动偏置调节螺杆
The cylinders are mounted to the brake pedal on one end, and a threaded brake bias screw on the other.
螺杆是由电子器件控制的 允许车手在赛中手动调节前后刹车比
This bias screw is electronically controlled and can be adjusted on the fly as directed by the driver.
螺杆的位置允许赛车前后刹车有不同的制动力
The screw position allows different pressure to the front or rear brakes.
刹车管路穿过悬架组件一路通到至制动钳或制动蹄
Brake lines snake through suspension elements to the brake caliper and shoe assembly.
制动产生的大量热量必须得到精确管理
Intense brake heat must be precisely managed.
因此整个车轮内侧制动导风管都被碳纤维保护罩覆盖
So the entire inner wheel assembly is covered by a ducted carbon fiber shroud.
前翼帮助引导气流进入制动导风管并通过车轮内侧进行冷却
The front wing helps direct air into the brake ducts and through the inner wheel for cooling.
卡钳被安装在尽可能低的位置 还要便于制动器能正常排气
The calipers are mounted at the lowest possible position for proper brake bleed,
在保证进入液压管路里的气泡能正常排出的同时
that is ensuring troublesome air bubbles can escape hydraulic brake lines,
还能尽可能降低车辆重心
while maintaining a low center of gravity.
刹车盘和刹车蹄由碳基材料制成
The brake disks and shoes are made from a carbon-based material,
刹车盘上有上千个小孔 从中心向外延伸 最大化冷却效果
The disk has thousands of small holes extending from the center outwards, for maximum cooling effect.
后制动器也有类似的设计策略
The rear brakes have a similar design strategy
近年来由于后轮制动靠新增的动能回收装置(MGU-K)来管理 体积有所变小
that have become smaller in recent years with the addition of the MGU-K, or motor generator unit kinetic.
MGU-K与曲轴相连 可以作为发电装置
The MGU-K is geared to the crankshaft and functions as an electrical power generator,
利用一部分后部制动力为车载电池充电
to charge an on-board battery as driven by a portion of rear braking forces.
安装在变速箱外壳内的计算机负责管理和平衡这套复杂的制动系统
A computer mounted inside the gearbox enclosure manages and balances this complex braking system.
车轮是用一颗车轮螺母固定在轮毂上的
The wheels are secured to the hub with a single wheel nut.
金属固定销将螺母牢牢固定
Metal retention pins keep the nut securely in place.
拆卸螺母时 会用专门的气枪先把这些销钉推进去
A specially designed wheel gun pushes these pins down when removing the nut.
发动机
及其相关系统
F1使用V6发动机
F1 cars use 6 cylinders in a V configuration.
活塞又平又小 以适应高转速的发动机
The pistons are somewhat flat and small to suit the high revving engine.
白神遥
交错纵横的排气管驱动发动机后部的一个巨大涡轮
Intricate exhaust headers feed a comparatively massive turbine at the rear of the engine
将这些通常叠在一起的涡轮组件分开 这是分体式涡轮增压器设计的一部分
which is part of a split turbocharger design that separates these normally stacked turbo components.
炽热的废气驱动涡轮
Red-hot exhaust gases drive the turbine wheel,
而涡轮又驱动安装在前面的压缩机轮
which in turn spins the front mounted compressor wheel,
吸入并压缩大量的空气
drawing in and compressing huge quantities of air.
但这些压力会给吸入的空气增加不必要的热量
All this pressure adds unwanted heat to the incoming air.
因此 一整个侧舱专门服务于中冷器
So one entire side pod is dedicated to the intercooler.
进入的空气路径是这样的
The path of incoming air looks like this.
压缩机通过安装在车手头顶后方主防滚架中的进气管将空气吸入
The compressor draws air in through an intake duct mounted in the roll hoop,
above and behind the driver's head.
热空气经过压缩机后流向中冷器
Hot air leaves the compressor towards the intercooler.
侧吊舱的空气高速流经中冷器的散热片 冷却里面的压缩空气
Side pod air rushes by the intercooler's tubes and fins, cooling the compressor air inside.
然后冷却的空气通过特殊的分体式管道 提供给各自独立的进气总成
The now cooled air passes through the special split ducting that feeds separate intake plenums.
这些腔室的设计可以保持气缸之间的气压平衡
These are chambers designed to keep air pressure balanced between cylinders.
进气口延伸至进气总成中 向每个气缸输送调整过的空气
Intake trumpets extend into the plenums for specially tuned air delivery to each cylinder.
侧吊舱的空气在从车尾排出之前还会流经并冷却发动机和其他内部零件
The side pod air flows by and cools the engine and other internal parts on its way
way out the back of the car.
涡轮机的排气部分有两个废气门 对应于每个排气口
The exhaust section of the turbo has dual waste gates corresponding to each exhaust input,
以便在需要时排出多余的气体
to vent off excess gases when needed.
废气门管道沿着主排气管排出车外
Waste gate pipes follow the main exhaust pipe out the back.
热能回收装置(MGU-H)位于这些涡轮组件之间
A high-tech heat recovery unit
sits between these turbo compartments called the MGU-H or motor generator unit heat.
MGU-H可以利用涡轮排出的多余热量为车载电池充电
Excess heat from turbo gases
drives this unit to act as an electric generator to charge the onboard battery.
能量回收系统
MGU-H和之前提到的MGU-K共同构成了现代F1赛车的混动部分
The MGU-H and the previously shown MGU-K together
make up the hybrid functionality of the modern F1 car.
这两个组件都可以为电池充电
Both units generate electrical charge for the battery.
而充电完成后 电池还可以把能量输送回MGU-K
Once sufficiently charged, the battery can send power back through the MGU-K unit,
而MGU-K又是与曲柄相连的
which again is geared to the crankshaft.
从而产生额外最多160马力的功率
In this way, the MGU-K can generate an additional maximum 160 horsepower,
和一个小型汽车发动机相当
or as much as a small separate car engine.
冷却系统
其他各种用于冷却的散热器几乎都在对侧的吊舱
Various additional radiators for cooling occupy the opposing side pod.
包括主发动机冷却散热器 机油冷却器和电池散热器
This includes the main engine cooling radiator, an oil cooler, and a battery cooler.
另外一组散热器位于主防滚架空气管道的路径上
An additional bank of radiators sits in the path of a separate roll hoop air duct,
用于冷却液压油 变速箱油 MGU-H和MGU-K
to cool hydraulic oil, gearbox oil, and the MGU-H&K systems.
F1各个车队可能将某个的散热器安装在与视频所示不同的位置
F1 teams may locate specific radiators in different positions than I've shown here,
但总归都在这一亩三分地里
though the general available spaces will be similar.
他们也可能使用水冷的中冷器来处理涡轮空气
They may also use water driven intercooling for turbo air,
与视频中的风冷不同
in contrast to the simpler air-to-air setup I've chosen.
燃料箱
油箱也被称为燃料舱 是一个凯夫拉材质的 防泄漏 内衬橡胶的油囊
The fuel tank also called a fuel cell, is a nearly puncture proof Kevlar bladder, lined with rubber.
它在碳纤维单体壳中完全独享一个包间
It occupies an isolated compartment in the carbon fiber monocoque shell, and fills all available space.
115-150升
F1油箱可以装载高达30-40加仑的燃油
F1 fuel cells can hold an incredible 30 to 40 gallons of fuel,
但却只够跑一场比赛使用 毕竟现在不让加油了
which is just enough for a single race as pit stop refueling is not allowed.
折合1.7-2.55公里/升
这些车每加仑的燃油约可行驶4至6英里
These cars get an estimated 4 to 6 miles per gallon of fuel.
油箱内有各种挡板和单向阀
The tank has various internal baffles with one-way valves
以克服液体在赛车各种极端运动下的晃动
to tame the sloshing liquid under incredible racing forces.
设计目标是让大部分的燃料保持在中心和低位
The goal is to keep the large fuel mass centered and low,
还要防止起泡 并保证燃料泵正常供给
and also to prevent foaming and fuel pump starvation.
发动机机油箱位于发动机与油箱之间
The engine oil tank is placed between the engine and fuel cell.
变速箱
实际上现在前进档有8个
八速变速箱 7个前进档 1个倒档
The eight-speed gearbox, seven forward plus one reverse,
位于发动机后面 在它自己的铝制外壳中
sits behind the engine in its own aluminum cartridge.
后差速器齿轮通过特殊的三脚架连接到后车桥
The rear differential gears connect to rear axles with special tripod joints,
使旋转的车桥能够随着后悬挂的移动而倾斜
that allow spinning axles to tilt with the rear suspension movement.
安全系统
F1赛车有着强大的安全系统
F1 cars have robust safety systems.
后部防撞结构可缓解后方撞击
The rear crash structure protects against rear impact.
侧面碰撞结构隐藏在车身空气动力学组件内
Side crash structures are concealed within the aerodynamic bodywork.
可拆卸的前翼部分可以缓解正面冲击
The removable front nose section handles front impact.
而最重要的单体结构在驾驶员周围形成了一个保护茧
And the all-important monocoque forms a protective cocoon around the driver.
另外在单体上
Also attached to the monocoque,
还有在2018年引入的HALO 进一步保护车手
a HALO device which was implemented in 2018 for additional driver safety.
还有一个主防滚架
And a roll hoop.
这句话相关内容见av762888754
车手的头盔必须位于主防滚架与车身的连线内
The driver's helmet is kept within a specific angle from the roll hoop to the body,
在翻车时最大程度地为车手提供保护
for maximum protection in the event of a rollover.
驾驶舱
F1赛车座椅根据车手身体外形特别定制的
F1 racing seats are crafted from molds, taken from a specific driver's body.
车手就像在吊床上一样半躺在里面
The driver sits in a reclined position almost like laying semi-upright in a hammock.
一条六点式安全带固定车手
A six-point harness keeps the driver in place.
座椅尽可能地包裹着车手的身体
The seat wraps around the driver's body wherever possible,
安全结构围绕着头盔区域
and safety structures surround the helmet area.
车手还会戴着头颈保护装置(HANS)
Drivers wear a special brace called the HANS, or head and neck device,
以限制突发情况下的头颈部运动
to limit head movement in adverse conditions.
有带子连接头盔的两侧
A connected strap clips to either side of the helmet,
而肩膀的安全带让HANS能够紧贴车手身体
and the shoulder harness straps keep the device pressed against the driver.
一根饮料管延伸到肩膀上
A drinks tube extends over the shoulder.
与一个小型储液器相连 保证车手能have the drink
It's connected to a small fluid reservoir to keep drivers hydrated while racing.
车手们还会有不同的头盔前部和后部扰流板设计
Drivers use different helmet front and rear spoiler designs
防止他们的头盔随着有时急剧变化的气流而抬起或移动
to keep their helmets from lifting or moving around with sometimes dramatically shifting air pressures.
近年来 遮阳板开口进一步缩小
In recent years the visor opening has further narrowed
保护脆弱的遮阳板区域不被刺穿或破裂
to protect the more fragile visor area from puncture or breakage.
驾驶舱的设计几乎榨干了内部的所有空间
Cockpit design makes efficient use of all available space
车手必须卸下方向盘才能离开赛车
such that drivers must remove the steering wheel to exit the car.
方向盘
这就是大名鼎鼎的F1赛车方向盘
This is the famed Formula 1 steering wheel.
车手不需要猛打轮 所以不用设计成圆形的
Drivers mostly don't need to remove their hands from the wheel for steering,
so the wheel doesn't need to be round.
中间的可定制显示屏将当前的档位醒目显示在中间
A customizable display at the center shows the current gear as the largest item,
同时还有圈速 轮胎和刹车温度 平均速度等信息
along with things like lap times tire and brake temperatures average speed and so on.
一堆眼花缭乱的旋钮 转盘和LED灯为车手和车队提供了更加精细的操控
The daunting array of knobs, dials and LEDs gives drivers and teams fine controls
车手可以随时在比赛中进行调整
that can be adjusted on the fly during a race.
从左上角开始顺时针方向依次是
Clockwise from the upper left,
控制MGU-H和MGU-K的能量回收系统拨盘
there's the energy recovery system dial to control the MGU-H&K,
左右菜单导航按钮
left and right menu navigation buttons,
用于车队通信的"一键通话"
a "push-to-talk radio switch" for team communication,
关键系统的LED警告灯
LED warning lights for critical systems,
显示屏顶部的一排LED作为转速计和换挡灯系统
a row of leds across the top of the display acts as a rev counter and shift light system,
发车控制开关 比赛开始时打开 比赛中关闭
the launch control switch which is turned on for race starts and off when racing,
刹车平衡旋钮 调整前后刹车比
the brake balance dial for front and rear brake bias,
维修区限速按钮 用于自动施加维修区限度和加速限制
a pit limits button to automatically impose things like pit lane speed and acceleration restrictions,
发动机映射旋钮 用于改变发动机性能特征
an engine mapping dial to alter engine performance characteristics,
DRS开关
DRS toggle button,
后差速器锁开关旋钮
rear differential lock open or closed adjustment,
入弯和出弯的调整是分开的
with separate turn entry and turn exit adjusters,
一键饮水按钮
the drinks dispenser button,
高级设置导航按钮
more settings navigation buttons,
发动机底盘或悬挂相关的三个可编程预设转盘
three programmable preset dials for the engine chassis or suspension,
以及用于潮湿天气或保胎之类的情景选择旋钮
and a scenario selector for things like wet weather or tire preservation presets,
空档按钮 因为无法用后拨片换挡器挂入空档和倒档
the neutral button is for neutral and reverse gears which can't be selected with rear paddle shifters,
一键收到按钮
a message OK button,
一键超车按钮 用于立即应用超车的最佳设置
an overtake button to instantly apply optimal settings for overtaking,
最后是一个液压设置表盘 用于控制变速箱和悬挂系统之类复杂的液压部件
and finally a hydraulic settings dial to control the complex hydraulic components,
spread throughout the car for example in the gearbox and suspension systems.
方向盘后面的拨片 上方两个用于换档
Paddles at the back of the steering wheel handle gear shifting up or down.
中间两个是车手可定制的功能
The middle paddles are driver customizable.
下面两个都是离合器 起步时只能用一个
And both bottom paddles actuate the clutch, only one clutch paddle can be used for race start.
车动起来后换档就不需要手动离合了
Once in motion the clutch isn't needed for gear shifting.
往驾驶舱下方看 右边是油门踏板
Further down into the cockpit we see the gas pedal,
它的轮廓包裹着驾驶员的脚 以便使两个踏板完全分离
with contours to wrap around the driver's foot so as to keep pedals completely separate,
左边是刹车踏板
and the brake pedal on the left.
传感器
赛车车身遍布传感器
There are sensors all over these cars.
比如前面有空速管 用于测量空速
For example, a pilot tube at the front measures air speed.
车手的定制耳塞还有加速度传感器来追踪头部运动
The driver's custom molded earplugs have an accelerometer to track head movement.
车尾还有麦克风 用于收集尾气声音
There's a microphone at the rear to pick up exhaust sound.
作为对比 旁边是一般体型的车手
Precise comparison, here's our average height driver model,
左边是一个一般大小的家用车 右边的是我们的F1赛车模型
standing beside an average sized car, next to our Formula model.
即使到现在画了20分钟讲这辆车的细节
It's important to note that even with the level of detail I've strived to attain here,
但现代F1赛车的复杂程度简直无穷无尽
the complexity in F1 cars feels almost endless,
简直极大考验我的查资料的能力
in a way that truly tested my research abilities.
它们简直是汽车机械的顶峰之作
They really are incredible racing machines.